<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Joseph Bisch</title>
    <link>http://josephbisch.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Joseph Bisch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://josephbisch.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Android</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/projects/android/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/projects/android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row-fluid&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;span12&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Android&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Advanced Live Wallpapers&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I created an Android Live Wallpaper app that features 3 OpenGL wallpapers. &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.josephbisch.anvancedlivewallpapers&#34;&gt;Available in the Google Play store.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Galaxy Live Wallpapers&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I created an Android Live Wallpaper app that features a rotating galaxy. Uses OpenGL. &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.josephbisch.galaxylivewallpaper&#34;&gt;Download it at the Google Play store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Battery Widget&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I created a Battery Widget app for Android. &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.josephbisch.batterywidget&#34;&gt;Download it at the Google Play store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atari</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/projects/atari/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/projects/atari/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row-fluid&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;span12&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Atari 8-bit&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;sio2pc&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I made an sio2pc using an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sparkfun.com/products/9716&#34;&gt;FTDI Basic Breakout&lt;/a&gt; from Sparkfun. Make sure to use the 5V one instead of the 3.3V one. I ran &lt;a href=&#34;http://sourceforge.net/projects/aspeqt/&#34;&gt;aspeqt&lt;/a&gt; on my PC. The sio2pc allows one to run disk images from the PC on the Atari and save files from the Atari to the PC.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Youtube videos&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The following are my Youtube videos on Atari:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OoyYS2w9Irk&#34;&gt;Atari Basic - Hello World and Etch-a-Sketch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/projects/debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/projects/debian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row-fluid&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;span12&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Debian&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At this time, this page mainly covers my contributions to Debian.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;My Start/GSoC 2014&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I started contributing to Debian when I applied to Debian for Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2014. I decided to apply for the Debian Metrics Portal project and I ended up being selected as the student to work on the project. Over the course of Summer 2014, I designed and implemented a website that stores and displays statistics about Debian. The website is available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://metrics.debian.net/&#34;&gt;http://metrics.debian.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Packaging&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I wanted to get involved in packaging software to go into the actual Debian OS, so after the summer I began working on packaging. I started with packaging a piece of software called Armory. Armory is a Bitcoin wallet, so I decided to start with it since I am interested in Bitcoin. In hindsight it was an ambitious first package, because it is such a large piece of software.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the meantime, while still working on Armory, I adopted two packages. One was slowaes and the other was winetricks. The slowaes package was simple to adopt. It was orphaned and no one seemed to be adopting it, so I went ahead and adopted it. I did so, because it was a dependency for electrum and I didn&#39;t want to see electrum removed from Debian. In the end, I just had to change the maintainer to myself and fix some policy issues. So It hasn&#39;t been much work to maintain. The other package, winetricks, was a little more work. The latest release in Debian was from January 2014, so I packaged a version from August 2014. Recently there were a couple bugs reported against winetricks due to sha1sum mismatches. One I probably will be able to fix in Jessie, due to the severity of the bug. However, the other one probably can&#39;t be fixed in Jessie due to the freeze.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Eventually I finished packaging Armory. It is currently only in unstable. It has been purposefully block from migrating to testing. That is so it remains easy to update Debian users to a new version of Armory. Otherwise, when testing becomes stable, users would be stuck on an outdated version of Armory.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Namecoin</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/projects/namecoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/projects/namecoin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row-fluid&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;span12&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Namecoin&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This page is mostly about my contributions to Namecoin.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;My Start&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My contributions to Namecoin started when I began working on adding Namecoin currency support to Armory. I had a question that I asked some Namecoin developers. From there I stuck around and worked on some other Namecoin projects.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;The Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My Armory repository ended up &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/namecoin/BitcoinArmory&#34;&gt;getting forked&lt;/a&gt; by the official Namecoin GitHub account. I also worked (or am working) on some stuff related to NMControl, most notably Python 3 support and an Android version called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/josephbisch/nmcontrolandroid&#34;&gt;NMControl for Android&lt;/a&gt;. I am also part of the group looking into build automation and reproducibility for Namecoin software.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>