<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Namecoin on Joseph Bisch</title>
    <link>http://josephbisch.com/tags/namecoin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Namecoin on Joseph Bisch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 07:25:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://josephbisch.com/tags/namecoin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Namecoin Block Format</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-12-15-namecoin-block-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 07:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-12-15-namecoin-block-format/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article assumes familiarity with the Bitcoin block format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Namecoin blocks starting with block 19200 may have some extra data in them. These blocks with extra data are called AuxPOW blocks for Auxiliary Proof of Work. The extra data appears between the nonce and txn_count. This extra data appears when a block has been merged-mined for both the Bitcoin and Namecoin networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that a Namecoin block after block 19200 may not be merged-mined, though most are. An important thing to note is that the hash of the block header for an AuxPOW block does not necessarily need to start with leading zeros like a regular block header&amp;rsquo;s hash (and generally it won&amp;rsquo;t start with leading zeros).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that confused me for a while was how to determine whether a block from block 19200 on is merged-mined or not. It turns out that you can use the version in the block header to determine that. If a block is merged-mined, the 0x100 digit will be set. The digit 0x10000 is used to signal that the auxiliary chain being merged-mined is Namecoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information including helpful diagrams, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Merged_mining_specification&#34;&gt;Bitcoin Wiki page on merged-mining&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing and Running nmcontrol</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-11-23-installing-and-running-nmcontrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 03:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-11-23-installing-and-running-nmcontrol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently installed the program nmcontrol. Doing so was non-trivial, so I am documenting the process I took here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those that don&amp;rsquo;t know, nmcontrol is a daemon that communicates with namecoind and provides services. In particular, I wanted to use the DNS service it provides for accessing .bit domain names. The .bit TLD is used by Namecoin. Namecoin is a decentalized key-value store and among its uses is decentalized DNS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/namecoin/nmcontrol.git&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd nmcontrol&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure namecoind is running in the background. You can do so by running &lt;code&gt;namecoind -daemon&lt;/code&gt;. Also make sure you have a namecoin.conf file in ~/.namecoin/namecoin.conf prior to running namecoind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to run nmcontrol as root for the DNS server to run on port 53, but you probably have Namecoin installed for your non-root user. So you need to link /root/.namecoin to point to ~/.namecoin. So run &lt;code&gt;sudo ln -s ~/.namecoin /root/.namecoin&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run nmcontrol by entering &lt;code&gt;sudo python nmcontrol.py&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you need to make sure your DNS is configured to use 127.0.0.1. You only need 127.0.0.1, because nmcontrol will use Google DNS servers to resolve non-.bit domain names. The exact instructions depend on which method of managing your network connections you use. I use Network Manager, so I right-clicked on the Network Manager applet and selected &amp;ldquo;Edit Connections&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;. Next I clicked on &amp;ldquo;Wireless&amp;rdquo;, selected my network, and clicked on &amp;ldquo;Edit&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;. I went to &amp;ldquo;IPv4 Settings&amp;rdquo;, and changed the &amp;ldquo;Method&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Automatic (DHCP) addresses only&amp;rdquo;. In &amp;ldquo;DNS servers&amp;rdquo; I entered 127.0.0.1 and clicked on the &amp;ldquo;Save&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; button. Then I clicked on &amp;ldquo;Close&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you need to restart Network Manager so that the changes will take effect. On Debian Wheezy, go to the terminal and type &lt;code&gt;sudo service network-manager restart&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go ahead and browse .bit domain names!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>