<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Joseph Bisch</title>
    <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Joseph Bisch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 08:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://josephbisch.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Angel Investing - April Update</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/2018-04-14-angel-investing-april-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/post/2018-04-14-angel-investing-april-update/</guid>
      <description>Since my first post about angel investing, I have made the following investments. These all happen to be YC W18 companies.
Vena Medical This company makes a camera that is small enough to fit inside blood vessels, providing a unique perspective to physicians.
Playbook This company makes an app to find other people to do things with. For example, you can find someone in the area who is also interested in playing basketball and do that together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angel Investing</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/2018-03-18-angel-investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 08:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/post/2018-03-18-angel-investing/</guid>
      <description>I started angel investing. I have two investments so far.
Sickweather This company has an app you can download to see what kind of sicknesses are going around in your area. You can also report what you have when you get sick.
Anyplace This company lets you live in a hotel on a month-to-month contract as an alternative to a traditional apartment lease. Also you don&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with furniture and utilities as you would with an apartment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More IRC Fuzzing</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/2017-10-01-more-irc-fuzzing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 19:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/post/2017-10-01-more-irc-fuzzing/</guid>
      <description>Background These are some results of my recent efforts of fuzzing IRC-related software.
CVE-2017-14727 in Weechat From the Weechat security page:
 Date/time conversion specifiers are expanded after replacing buffer local variables in name of log files. In some cases, this can lead to an error in function strftime and a crash caused by the use of an uninitialized buffer. Workaround: Unload the logger plugin: /plugin unload logger
 Mitre CVE Page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding a Bug in SQLite by Fuzzing osquery</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/2016-12-02-finding-a-bug-in-sqlite-by-fuzzing-osquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 13:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/post/2016-12-02-finding-a-bug-in-sqlite-by-fuzzing-osquery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While fuzzing osquery using afl, I encountered a bug in SQLite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;investigation-of-the-bug&#34;&gt;Investigation of the Bug&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bug was reproducible using &lt;code&gt;printf &amp;quot;select * from routes where destination ;VACUUM &#39;::1&#39;;\n&amp;quot; | osqueryi&lt;/code&gt;. Using osquery binaries compiled with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AddressSanitizer&#34;&gt;ASan&lt;/a&gt;, I got a heap-use-after-free report when running the osqueryi program as demonstrated in the previous sentence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Irssi Bug #563</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/2016-10-30-irssi-bug-563/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 17:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/post/2016-10-30-irssi-bug-563/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While fuzzing irssi&amp;rsquo;s config file parser using afl, I encountered a bug that I reported and became &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/irssi/irssi/issues/563&#34;&gt;issue #563&lt;/a&gt; for irssi on GitHub. I am going to perform an analysis of the bug and my solution to the bug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I had to do to build irssi with afl was add &lt;code&gt;CC=/path/to/afl/afl-gcc&lt;/code&gt; to the configure script invocation. After building irssi, I started running &lt;code&gt;irssi --config file.cfg&lt;/code&gt; with afl, allowing afl to pass in the configuration file it generates in place of file.cfg. All that can be done by following a guide that covers how to use afl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Laptop</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/2015-12-13-new-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2015 20:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/post/2015-12-13-new-laptop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got a new laptop. It is the HP Pavilion 15t. The model number is 15t-ab100 and the SKU is L8V46AV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the i5 processor with 8 GB RAM and 1 TB HDD. It was a big upgrade over my old laptop, because I had a first gen i3 in the old one and this has a Skylake processor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Namecoin Block Format</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-12-15-namecoin-block-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 07:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-12-15-namecoin-block-format/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article assumes familiarity with the Bitcoin block format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Namecoin blocks starting with block 19200 may have some extra data in them. These blocks with extra data are called AuxPOW blocks for Auxiliary Proof of Work. The extra data appears between the nonce and txn_count. This extra data appears when a block has been merged-mined for both the Bitcoin and Namecoin networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing and Running nmcontrol</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-11-23-installing-and-running-nmcontrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 03:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-11-23-installing-and-running-nmcontrol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently installed the program nmcontrol. Doing so was non-trivial, so I am documenting the process I took here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those that don&amp;rsquo;t know, nmcontrol is a daemon that communicates with namecoind and provides services. In particular, I wanted to use the DNS service it provides for accessing .bit domain names. The .bit TLD is used by Namecoin. Namecoin is a decentalized key-value store and among its uses is decentalized DNS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Package</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-09-04-my-first-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 10:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-09-04-my-first-package/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got my first package uploaded to Debian this week. That package is winetricks. It was orphaned and I adopted it. Now the lastest version (0.0+20140818+svn1202) is available in sid and should migrate to testing in nine days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debconf Wrapup</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-09-01-debconf-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 14:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-09-01-debconf-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Debconf14 was the first Debconf I attended. It was an awesome experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Debconf14 started with a Meet and Greet before the Welcome Talk. I got to meet people and find out what they do for Debian. I also got to meet other GSoC students that I had only previously interacted with online. During the Meet and Greet I also met one of my mentors for GSoC, Zack. Later in the conference I met another of my mentors, Piotr. Previously I only interacted with Zack and Piotr online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Update</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-07-11-gsoc-update-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-07-11-gsoc-update-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a couple of months since my last GSoC update and a lot has happened since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://metrics.debian.net&#34;&gt;view the web interface at metrics.debian.net&lt;/a&gt;. There is a dynamic interface viewable with JavaScript enabled, and a static interface viewable with JS disabled. I am currently working on the dynamic interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Welcome Package Received</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-05-01-gsoc-welcome-package-received/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-05-01-gsoc-welcome-package-received/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple days ago I received my welcome package from Google. The welcome package included a pen and a notepad that has stickers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Summer of Code</title>
      <link>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-04-22-a-summer-of-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://josephbisch.com/post/2014-04-22-a-summer-of-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I found out that I was accepted into the Google Summer of Code program. I was accepted by Debian and will be working on a Metrics Portal. You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://bits.debian.org/2014/04/welcome-gsoc-students-2014.html&#34;&gt;view the announcement on the Debian blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>